{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "_______ 、えいがをみにいきませんか？",
      "options": [
        "ゆうべ ( 昨夜 )",
        "きのう ( 昨日 )",
        "あした ( 明日 )",
        "おととい ( 一昨日 )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "あした ( 明日 )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Last night",
        "Yesterday",
        "Tomorrow",
        "Day before yesterday"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "Would you like to go see a movie tomorrow?"
    },
    {
      "question": "わたしはいつも　_______ をききながらべんきょうします。",
      "options": ["ぺん", "ラジオ", "テーブル", "ストーブ"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "ラジオ",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Pen", "Radio", "Rable", "Stove"],
      "questionTranslate": "I always study while listening to the radio."
    },
    {
      "question": "わたしのすきなのみものは　_______ です。",
      "options": [
        "おかし ( お菓子 )",
        "こうちゃ ( 紅茶 )",
        "みかん ( 蜜柑 )",
        "ねこ ( 猫 )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "こうちゃ ( 紅茶 )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Sweets/Candy",
        "Black tea",
        "Tangerine/Mandarin orange",
        "Cat"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "My favorite drink is black tea."
    },
    {
      "question": "わたしはじてんしゃを　_______ もっています。",
      "options": [
        "にだい ( 二台 )",
        "にさつ ( 二冊 )",
        "にほん ( 二本 )",
        "にまい ( 二枚 )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "にだい ( 二台 )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "DAI is counter for machines or vehicle",
        "SATSU is counter for books",
        "HON/PON counter for long cylindrical things",
        "MAI is counter for thin, flat objects"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "I have (two) bicycles."
    },
    {
      "question": "この　_______ じしょはだれのですか？",
      "options": [
        "ほそい ( 細い )",
        "まるい ( 丸い )",
        "みじかい ( 短い )",
        "ちいさい ( 小さい )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "ちいさい ( 小さい )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Thin", "Round", "Short", "Small"],
      "questionTranslate": "Whose is this small dictionary?"
    },
    {
      "question": "ちちはことし80さいですが、_______ です。",
      "options": [
        "げんき ( 元気 )",
        "けっこう ( 結構 )",
        "ざんねん ( 残念 )",
        "かんたん ( 簡単 )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "げんき ( 元気 )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Healthy",
        "Fine",
        "Regret/Disappointment/Sorry",
        "Easy"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "My father is 80 years old this year, but he is in good health."
    },
    {
      "question": "あめがふっています。みんなかさを　_______ います。",
      "options": [
        "あけて ( 開けて )",
        "あげて ( 上げて )",
        "さして ( 差して )",
        "つけて ( 付けて )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "さして ( 差して )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Open a door", "Raise", "Holding", "Attach"],
      "questionTranslate": "Its raining. Everyone is holding an umbrella."
    },
    {
      "question": "がくせいたちはきょうしつでやまだせんせいににほんごを　_______ います。",
      "options": [
        "ならって ( 習って )",
        "つくって ( 使う )",
        "おぼえて ( 覚えて )",
        "べんきょうして ( 勉強して )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "ならって ( 習って )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["To learn", "To make", "Remember", "Study"],
      "questionTranslate": "The students are learning Japanese from Yamada Sensei at school."
    },
    {
      "question": "やまださんはあかいぼうしを　_______ います。",
      "options": [
        "きて ( 来て )",
        "しめて ( 締めて )",
        "はいって ( 入って )",
        "かぶって ( 被って )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "かぶって ( 被って )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Come", "Tighten", "To enter", "To put on (head)"],
      "questionTranslate": "Mr. Yamada is wearing a red hat."
    },
    {
      "question": "やまださんはたいていおふろにはいって、_______ ねます。",
      "options": [
        "ちょうど ( 丁度 )",
        "すぐに ( 直ぐに )",
        "まだ",
        "だんだん ( 段々 )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "すぐに ( 直ぐに )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Exactly/just right",
        "Immediately/Right away",
        "Not yet/Still",
        "Gradually"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "Mr. Yamada usually takes a bath and goes to sleep right away."
    },
    {
      "question": "なのかのつぎは　_______ です。",
      "options": [
        "とおか ( 10日 )",
        "ようか ( 8日 )",
        "むいか ( 6日 )",
        "よっか ( 4日 )"
      ],
      "Set": "2",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "ようか ( 8日 )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["ten days", "8 days", "6 days", "4 days"],
      "questionTranslate": "Next up after 7 is 8th."
    },
    {
      "question": "わたしはゆうべともだちに　_______ をかきました。",
      "options": [
        "ふうとう ( 封筒 )",
        "きって ( 切って )",
        "でんわ ( 電話 )",
        "てがみ ( 手紙 )"
      ],
      "Set": "2",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "てがみ ( 手紙 )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Envelope", "Cut", "Phone", "Letter"],
      "questionTranslate": "I wrote a letter to my friend last night."
    },
    {
      "question": "わたしのすきなスポーツは　_______ です。",
      "options": ["ピアノ", "レコード", "スキー", "テーブル"],
      "Set": "2",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "スキー",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Piano", "Record", "Ski", "Table"],
      "questionTranslate": "My favorite sport is skiing."
    },
    {
      "question": "わたしのうちにねこが　_______ います。",
      "options": [
        "ふたつ ( 2つ )",
        "ふたり ( 二人 )",
        "にだい ( ２台 )",
        "にひき ( 2匹 )"
      ],
      "Set": "2",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "にひき ( 2匹 )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Two (objects)",
        "Two people",
        "DAI is counter for machines or vehicle",
        "HIKI is counter for for small animals"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "I have two cats in my house."
    },
    {
      "question": "このみちは　_______ です。",
      "options": [
        "わかい ( 若い )",
        "うすい ( 薄い )",
        "せまい ( 狭い )",
        "おもい ( 重い )"
      ],
      "Set": "2",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "せまい ( 狭い )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Young", "Thin", "Narrow", "Heavy"],
      "questionTranslate": "This road is narrow"
    },
    {
      "question": "さかながかわを　_______ います。",
      "options": [
        "およいで ( 泳いで )",
        "はしって ( 走って )",
        "あるいて ( 歩いて )",
        "とんで ( 飛んで )"
      ],
      "Set": "2",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "およいで ( 泳いで )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Swimming", "Run", "Walk", "Flying"],
      "questionTranslate": "Fish are swimming in the river"
    },
    {
      "question": "きのうのパーテイーでやまださんに　_______ あいました。",
      "options": [
        "はじめ ( 始めて )",
        "はじめて ( 初めて )",
        "はじめの ( 始めの )",
        "はじめから ( 始めから )"
      ],
      "Set": "2",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "はじめて ( 初めて )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Start/Beginning",
        "For the first time",
        "The beginning",
        "From the beginning"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "I met Mr. Yamada for the first time at a party yesterday."
    },
    {
      "question": "たなかさんはきょうはあおいズボンを　_______ います。",
      "options": [
        "かぶって ( 被って )",
        "はいて ( 履いて )",
        "きて ( 着る )",
        "かけて ( 掛けて )"
      ],
      "Set": "2",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "はいて ( 履いて )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "To wear on head",
        "To wear on lower body",
        "To wear upper body",
        "To wear (eyeglass, necklace)"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "Tanaka-san is wearing blue pants today."
    },
    {
      "question": "えきででんしゃに　_______ ます。",
      "options": [
        "のり ( 乗り )",
        "とり ( 取り )",
        "すわり ( 座り )",
        "のぼり ( 登り )"
      ],
      "Set": "2",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "のり ( 乗り )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Ride", "Take", "Sit", "Climb"],
      "questionTranslate": "Im going to take a ride on the train."
    },
    {
      "question": "まちださんはせが　_______ です。",
      "options": [
        "とおい ( 遠い )",
        "ながい ( 長い )",
        "おもい ( 重い )",
        "たかい ( 高い )"
      ],
      "Set": "2",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "たかい ( 高い )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Far", "Long", "Heavy", "Tall/High/Expensive"],
      "questionTranslate": "Mr. Machida is tall."
    },
    {
      "question": "わたしはよるねるまえにはを _______ 。",
      "options": [
        "あらいます ( 洗う )",
        "つかいます ( 使う )",
        "あびます ( あびる )",
        "みがきます ( 磨く )"
      ],
      "Set": "3",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "みがきます ( 磨く )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "To Wash, To Cleanse, To Rinse",
        "To Use (A Tool, Method, Etc.), To Make Use Of, To Put To Use",
        "To Take (E.G. Shower), To Bathe In",
        "To Polish, To Shine, To Scrub, To Brush (Teeth)"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "I brush my teeth before I go to bed."
    },
    {
      "question": "つぎのかどをみぎに _______ 。",
      "options": [
        "まがります ( 曲がる )",
        "わたります ( 渡る )",
        "のぼります ( 登る )",
        "とまります ( 止まる )"
      ],
      "Set": "3",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "まがります ( 曲がる )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "To Bend, To Curve, To Warp, To Wind, To Twist",
        "To Cross Over, To Go Across",
        "To Ascend, To Go Up, To Climb",
        "To Stop (Moving), To Come To A Stop"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "Turn right at the end of the street."
    },
    {
      "question": "わたしの　いえは　えきの　ちかくです。とても _______ です。",
      "options": [
        "べんり ( 便利 )",
        "ひま ( 暇 )",
        "じょうず ( 上手 )",
        "いろいろ ( 色々 )"
      ],
      "Set": "3",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "べんり ( 便利 )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Convenient, Handy, Useful",
        "Spare Time, Free Time, Leisure",
        "Skillful, Skilled, Proficient, Good (At), Adept, Clever",
        "Various, All Sorts Of, Variety Of"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "My house is near the station. Its very convenient."
    },
    {
      "question": "かぜを _______ 、かいしゃをやすみました。",
      "options": ["やって", "なって", "ふいて ( 吹く )", "ひいて ( 引く )"],
      "Set": "3",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "ひいて ( 引く )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "To Do, To Undertake, To Perform, To Play (A Game), To Study",
        "To Become, To Get, To Grow",
        "To Blow (Of The Wind)",
        "To Pull"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "I caught a cold and took a day off from work."
    },
    {
      "question": "まいつきほんを _______ よみます。",
      "options": [
        "さんさつ ( 三冊 )",
        "さんだい ( 三代 )",
        "さんぼん ( ３本 )",
        "さんまい ( 三枚 )"
      ],
      "Set": "3",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "さんさつ ( 三冊 )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Counter For Books",
        "Counter For Vehicles And Big Equipment",
        "Counter For Long And Round Objects",
        "Counter For Flat And Thin Objects"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "I read three books every month."
    },
    {
      "question": "きのう _______ にほんのえいがをみました。",
      "options": [
        "どきどき ( 時々 )",
        "もちろん",
        "はじめに ( 初めに )",
        "はじめて ( 初めて )"
      ],
      "Set": "3",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "はじめて ( 初めて )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Sometimes, Occasionally,",
        "Of Course, Certainly, Naturally",
        "To Begin With, First Of All",
        "For The First Time"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "Yesterday I watched a Japanese movie for the first time."
    },
    {
      "question": "きのうかぞくのしゃしんを _______ 。",
      "options": [
        "とりました ( 取る )",
        "つくりました ( 作る )",
        "かきました ( 書く )",
        "しました"
      ],
      "Set": "3",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "とりました ( 取る )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "To Take, To Pick Up, To Grab, To Catch",
        "To Make, To Produce, To Prepare (Food)",
        "To Write, To Compose",
        " To Do, To Carry Out, To Perform"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "I took a family photo yesterday."
    },
    {
      "question": "_______ をしめてかいしゃへいきます。",
      "options": ["セーター", "シャツ", "ズボン", "ネクタイ"],
      "Set": "3",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "ネクタイ",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Sweater", "Shirt", "Pants", "Necktie"],
      "questionTranslate": "I put on my tie and go to work."
    },
    {
      "question": "それはとても _______ もんだいです。",
      "options": [
        "たいせつな ( 大切 )",
        "いろいろな ( 色々 )",
        "じょうぶな ( 丈夫な )",
        "にぎやかな ( 賑やか )"
      ],
      "Set": "3",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "たいせつな ( 大切 )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Important, Significant",
        "Various",
        "Healthy, Robust",
        "Bustling, Busy"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "That is a very important issue."
    },
    {
      "question": " なつはまいにち　_______ へおよぎにいきます。",
      "options": ["えき ( 駅 )", "みせ ( 店 )", "プール", "テーブル"],
      "Set": "3",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "プール",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Train Station",
        "Store, Shop, Establishment",
        "Pool",
        "Table"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "In the summer, I go to the pool to swim every day."
    },

    {
      "question": "日本では、はる·なつ·あき·ふゆの四つの _______ があります。",
      "options": [
        "てんき ( 天気 )",
        "きぶん ( 気分 )",
        "きおん ( 気温 )",
        "きせつ ( 季節 )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "4",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "きせつ ( 季節 )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Weather", "Feeling/Mood", "Temperature", "season"],
      "questionTranslate": "In Japan, there are four seasons: spring, summer, snow, and winter."
    },
    {
      "question": "きのうならったことをもう _______ しまいました。",
      "options": [
        "わすれて ( 忘れて )",
        "すてて ( 捨てて )",
        "なくして ( 亡くして )",
        "とって ( 取って )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "4",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "わすれて ( 忘れて )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Forget", "Throw away", "Lost", "Take"],
      "questionTranslate": "I have already forgotten what I learned yesterday."
    },
    {
      "question": "シャツのうりばは、このうえの３がいです。あの _______ でいってください。",
      "options": ["ドア", "タクシー", "サンダル", "エスカレーター"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "4",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "エスカレーター",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Door", "Taxi", "Sandal", "Escalator"],
      "questionTranslate": "The shirt department is on the third floor above this. Please take that escalator."
    },
    {
      "question": "あまり勉強しなかったので、テストのてんが _______ です。",
      "options": [
        "しんぱい ( 心配 )",
        "きけん ( 危険 )",
        "あんぜん ( 安全 )",
        "あんしん ( 安心 )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "4",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "しんぱい ( 心配 )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Worry", "Danger", "Safe", "Relief/Rest assured"],
      "questionTranslate": "I didnt study much, so Im worried about my test score."
    },
    {
      "question": "おもしろいえいがだと聞いたので、_______ みたいです。",
      "options": [
        "たぶん ( 多分 )",
        "そんなに",
        "ぜひ ( 是非 )",
        "きゅうに ( 急に )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "4",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "ぜひ ( 是非 )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Probably/Maybe",
        "That much",
        "Cetainly/Without fail",
        "Suddenly/Unexpected"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "I heard its an interesting movie, so I definitely want to see it."
    },
    {
      "question": "たかださんは _______ をしながらだいがくにかよっています。",
      "options": ["オートバイ", "デパート", "アルバイト", "カレンダー"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "4",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "アルバイト",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Motorcycle",
        "Department store",
        "Part-time job",
        "Calendar"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "Takada is attending university while working part-time."
    },
    {
      "question": "はなこさんは白いスカートと _______ をはいています。",
      "options": ["セーター", "ハンカチ", "サンダル", "オーバー"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "4",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "サンダル",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Sweater", "Handkerchief", "Sandal", "Over"],
      "questionTranslate": "Hanako is wearing a white skirt and sandals."
    },
    {
      "question": "父はとうきょうへ行くと、いつも _______ をかってきてくれます。",
      "options": [
        "おまつり ( お祭り )",
        "おれい ( お礼 )",
        "おみやげ ( お土産 )",
        "おいわい ( お祝い )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "4",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "おみやげ ( お土産 )",
      "optionsTranslate": [
        "Festival",
        "Thank-you",
        "Presents/Souvenir",
        "Celebration"
      ],
      "questionTranslate": "When my father goes to Tokyo, he always brings me souvenirs."
    },
    {
      "question": "あのあたらしい _______ はデパートです。",
      "options": ["アパート", "ホテル", "プール", "ビル"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "4",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "ビル",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Apartment", "Hotel", "Pool", "Building"],
      "questionTranslate": "That new building is a department store."
    },
    {
      "question": " じゅぎょうがおわってから、まいにち、ピンポンの _______ をします。",
      "options": [
        "しゅみ ( 趣味 )",
        "うんどう ( 運動 )",
        "れんしゅう ( 練習 )",
        "しゅうかん ( 習慣 )"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "4",
      "type": "vocab",
      "answer": "れんしゅう ( 練習 )",
      "optionsTranslate": ["Hobby", "Exercise", "Practice", "Habit"],
      "questionTranslate": "After school is over, we practice ping pong every day."
    },
    {
      "question": "まいにちしんぶん　_______ 読みます。",
      "options": ["へ", "を", "に", "が"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "grammar",
      "answer": "を",
      "optionsTranslate": ["", "", "", ""],
      "questionTranslate": "I read the newspaper every day"
    },
    {
      "question": "田中さんは　_______ 来ていませんよ。",
      "options": ["もう", "だけ", "まだ", "まで"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "grammar",
      "answer": "まだ",
      "optionsTranslate": ["", "", "", ""],
      "questionTranslate": "Mr. Tanaka hasnt come yet."
    },
    {
      "question": "ナイフ　_______ パンをきりました。",
      "options": ["で", "を", "に", "が"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "grammar",
      "answer": "で",
      "optionsTranslate": ["", "", "", ""],
      "questionTranslate": "I cut the bread with a knife."
    },
    {
      "question": "家にかえってねたほう　_______ いいですよ。",
      "options": ["と", "に", "が", "は"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "grammar",
      "answer": "が",
      "optionsTranslate": ["", "", "", ""],
      "questionTranslate": "It is better to go home and sleep."
    },
    {
      "question": "お母さん、もうあそびに　_______ もいいですか？",
      "options": ["行く", "行って", "行った", "行っている"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "grammar",
      "answer": "行って",
      "optionsTranslate": ["", "", "", ""],
      "questionTranslate": "Mom, can I go play now?"
    },
    {
      "question": "すいようびには日本語のテスト　_______ 。",
      "options": ["はいます", "はあります", "がいます", "があります"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "grammar",
      "answer": "があります",
      "optionsTranslate": ["", "", "", ""],
      "questionTranslate": "There is a Japanese Test on Wednesday."
    },
    {
      "question": "あなたのかみは　_______ よ。",
      "options": [
        "長ってすぎます",
        "長くすぎます",
        "長いすぎます",
        "長すぎます"
      ],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "grammar",
      "answer": "長すぎます",
      "optionsTranslate": ["", "", "", ""],
      "questionTranslate": "Your hair is too long."
    },
    {
      "question": "わたしはけいかんに　_______ です。",
      "options": ["なりたい", "したい", "いきたい", "いたい"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "grammar",
      "answer": "なりたい",
      "optionsTranslate": ["", "", "", ""],
      "questionTranslate": "I would like to be a police officer."
    },
    {
      "question": "わたしは、これから　_______ に行きます。",
      "options": ["およぐ", "およいで", "およぎ", "およいだ"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "grammar",
      "answer": "およぎ",
      "optionsTranslate": ["", "", "", ""],
      "questionTranslate": "I am going swimming now."
    },
    {
      "question": " あの人たちはどこに行っているん　_______ 。",
      "options": ["だろう", "つもりだ", "から", "けれども"],
      "Set": "1",
      "level": "5",
      "type": "grammar",
      "answer": "だろう",
      "optionsTranslate": ["", "", "", ""],
      "questionTranslate": "I wonder where those people are going."
    }
  ],
  "alphabet": [
    {
      "hiragana": "あ",
      "katakana": "ア",
      "romaji": "a",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "a"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "い",
      "katakana": "イ",
      "romaji": "i",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "a"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "う",
      "katakana": "ウ",
      "romaji": "u",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "a"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "え",
      "katakana": "エ",
      "romaji": "e",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "a"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "お",
      "katakana": "オ",
      "romaji": "o",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "a"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "か",
      "katakana": "カ",
      "romaji": "ka",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ka"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "き",
      "katakana": "キ",
      "romaji": "ki",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ka"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "く",
      "katakana": "ク",
      "romaji": "ku",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ka"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "け",
      "katakana": "ケ",
      "romaji": "ke",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ka"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "こ",
      "katakana": "コ",
      "romaji": "ko",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ka"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "さ",
      "katakana": "サ",
      "romaji": "sa",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "sa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "し",
      "katakana": "シ",
      "romaji": "shi",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "sa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "す",
      "katakana": "ス",
      "romaji": "su",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "sa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "せ",
      "katakana": "セ",
      "romaji": "se",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "sa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "そ",
      "katakana": "ソ",
      "romaji": "so",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "sa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "た",
      "katakana": "タ",
      "romaji": "ta",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ta"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ち",
      "katakana": "チ",
      "romaji": "chi",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ta"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "つ",
      "katakana": "ツ",
      "romaji": "tsu",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ta"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "て",
      "katakana": "テ",
      "romaji": "te",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ta"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "と",
      "katakana": "ト",
      "romaji": "to",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ta"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "な",
      "katakana": "ナ",
      "romaji": "na",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "na"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "に",
      "katakana": "ニ",
      "romaji": "ni",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "na"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぬ",
      "katakana": "ヌ",
      "romaji": "nu",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "na"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ね",
      "katakana": "ネ",
      "romaji": "ne",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "na"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "の",
      "katakana": "ノ",
      "romaji": "no",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "na"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "は",
      "katakana": "ハ",
      "romaji": "ha",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ひ",
      "katakana": "ヒ",
      "romaji": "hi",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ふ",
      "katakana": "フ",
      "romaji": "fu",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "へ",
      "katakana": "ヘ",
      "romaji": "he",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ほ",
      "katakana": "ホ",
      "romaji": "ho",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ま",
      "katakana": "マ",
      "romaji": "ma",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ma"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "み",
      "katakana": "ミ",
      "romaji": "mi",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ma"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "む",
      "katakana": "ム",
      "romaji": "mu",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ma"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "め",
      "katakana": "メ",
      "romaji": "me",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ma"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "も",
      "katakana": "モ",
      "romaji": "mo",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ma"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "や",
      "katakana": "ヤ",
      "romaji": "ya",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ゆ",
      "katakana": "ユ",
      "romaji": "yu",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "よ",
      "katakana": "ヨ",
      "romaji": "yo",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ら",
      "katakana": "ラ",
      "romaji": "ra",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ra"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "り",
      "katakana": "リ",
      "romaji": "ri",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ra"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "る",
      "katakana": "ル",
      "romaji": "ru",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ra"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "れ",
      "katakana": "レ",
      "romaji": "re",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ra"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ろ",
      "katakana": "ロ",
      "romaji": "ro",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "ra"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "わ",
      "katakana": "ハ",
      "romaji": "wa",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "wa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "を",
      "katakana": "オ",
      "romaji": "wo",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "wa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ん",
      "katakana": "ン",
      "romaji": "n",
      "mode": "main",
      "group": "wa"
    },

    {
      "hiragana": "にゃ",
      "katakana": "ニャ",
      "romaji": "nya",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "nya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "にゅ",
      "katakana": "ニュ",
      "romaji": "nyu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "nya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "にょ",
      "katakana": "ニョ",
      "romaji": "nyo",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "nya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ちゃ",
      "katakana": "チャ",
      "romaji": "cha",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "cha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ちゅ",
      "katakana": "チュ",
      "romaji": "chu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "cha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ちょ",
      "katakana": "チョ",
      "romaji": "cho",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "cha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "しゃ",
      "katakana": "シャ",
      "romaji": "sha",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "sha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "しゅ",
      "katakana": "シュ",
      "romaji": "shu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "sha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "しょ",
      "katakana": "ショ",
      "romaji": "sho",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "sha"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "きゃ",
      "katakana": "キャ",
      "romaji": "kya",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "kya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "きゅ",
      "katakana": "キュ",
      "romaji": "kyu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "kya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "きょ",
      "katakana": "キョ",
      "romaji": "kyo",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "kya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぎゃ",
      "katakana": "ギャ",
      "romaji": "gya",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "gya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぎゅ",
      "katakana": "ギュ",
      "romaji": "gyu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "gya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぎょ",
      "katakana": "ギョ",
      "romaji": "gyo",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "gya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "りゃ",
      "katakana": "リャ",
      "romaji": "rya",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "rya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "りゅ",
      "katakana": "リュ",
      "romaji": "ryu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "rya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "りょ",
      "katakana": "リョ",
      "romaji": "ryo",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "rya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "みゃ",
      "katakana": "ミャ",
      "romaji": "mya",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "mya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "みゅ",
      "katakana": "ミュ",
      "romaji": "myu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "mya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "みょ",
      "katakana": "ミョ",
      "romaji": "myo",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "mya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ひゃ",
      "katakana": "ヒャ",
      "romaji": "hya",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "hya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ひゅ",
      "katakana": "ヒュ",
      "romaji": "hyu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "hya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ひょ",
      "katakana": "ヒョ",
      "romaji": "hyo",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "hya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぴゃ",
      "katakana": "ピャ",
      "romaji": "pya",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "pya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぴゅ",
      "katakana": "ピュ",
      "romaji": "pyu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "pya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぴょ",
      "katakana": "ピョ",
      "romaji": "pyo",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "pya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "びゃ",
      "katakana": "ビャ",
      "romaji": "bya",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "bya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "びゅ",
      "katakana": "ビュ",
      "romaji": "byu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "bya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "びょ",
      "katakana": "ビョ",
      "romaji": "byo",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "bya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "じゃ",
      "katakana": "ジャ",
      "romaji": "ja",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "ja"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "じゅ",
      "katakana": "ジュ",
      "romaji": "ju",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "ja"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "じょ",
      "katakana": "ジョ",
      "romaji": "jo",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "ja"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぢゃ",
      "katakana": "ヂャ",
      "romaji": "dya",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "dya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぢゅ",
      "katakana": "ヂュ",
      "romaji": "dyu",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "dya"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぢょ",
      "katakana": "ぢょ",
      "romaji": "dyo",
      "mode": "combination",
      "group": "dya"
    },

    {
      "hiragana": "ば",
      "katakana": "バ",
      "romaji": "ba",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "ba"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "び",
      "katakana": "ビ",
      "romaji": "bi",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "ba"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぶ",
      "katakana": "ブ",
      "romaji": "bu",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "ba"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "べ",
      "katakana": "ベ",
      "romaji": "be",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "ba"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぼ",
      "katakana": "ボ",
      "romaji": "bo",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "ba"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "だ",
      "katakana": "ダ",
      "romaji": "da",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "da"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぢ",
      "katakana": "ヂ",
      "romaji": "di",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "da"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "づ",
      "katakana": "ヅ",
      "romaji": "du",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "da"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "で",
      "katakana": "デ",
      "romaji": "de",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "da"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ど",
      "katakana": "ド",
      "romaji": "do",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "da"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ざ",
      "katakana": "ザ",
      "romaji": "za",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "za"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "じ",
      "katakana": "ジ",
      "romaji": "ji",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "za"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ず",
      "katakana": "ズ",
      "romaji": "zu",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "za"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぜ",
      "katakana": "ゼ",
      "romaji": "ze",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "za"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぞ",
      "katakana": "ゾ",
      "romaji": "zo",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "za"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "が",
      "katakana": "ガ",
      "romaji": "ga",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "ga"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぎ",
      "katakana": "ギ",
      "romaji": "gi",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "ga"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぐ",
      "katakana": "グ",
      "romaji": "gu",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "ga"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "げ",
      "katakana": "ゲ",
      "romaji": "ge",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "ga"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ご",
      "katakana": "ゴ",
      "romaji": "go",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "ga"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぱ",
      "katakana": "パ",
      "romaji": "pa",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "pa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぴ",
      "katakana": "ピ",
      "romaji": "pi",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "pa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぷ",
      "katakana": "プ",
      "romaji": "pu",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "pa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぺ",
      "katakana": "ペ",
      "romaji": "pe",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "pa"
    },
    {
      "hiragana": "ぽ",
      "katakana": "ポ",
      "romaji": "po",
      "mode": "dakuten",
      "group": "pa"
    }
  ]
}
